<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ens on 秋来冬风的博客</title>
    <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ens on 秋来冬风的博客</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:50:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Cloudflare Argo Smart Routing   Greatly Improving Access Speed in Chinese Mainland</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/my-experience-with-cloudflare-argo-smart-routing---greatly-improving-access-speed-in-chinese-mainland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:50:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/my-experience-with-cloudflare-argo-smart-routing---greatly-improving-access-speed-in-chinese-mainland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s free plan provides unlimited CDN, DDoS protection, and a 15 year source server TLS certificate, among other useful services, which are very helpful for building websites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This cannot use nodes located in Chinese Mainland. All data is transferred from overseas (outside Chinese Mainland) to Chinese Mainland. According to their sales staff, only nodes with less than 20% Cloudflare can be used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After using the free plan, it may take nearly 50 seconds to load the website when you visit the website through http3 at night in Chinese Mainland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Guide to Choosing VPS (Virtual Private Server)</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/personal-guide-to-choosing-vps-virtual-private-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/personal-guide-to-choosing-vps-virtual-private-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VPS (Virtual Private Server) is based on virtualization technology, which divides a physical server into multiple virtual servers, allowing users to obtain servers at a lower cost.&#xA;This guide is intended for personal use, such as learning and research, lightweight websites (personal blogs), etc. But other uses, such as commercial websites, also have reference value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-should-i-choose-vps&#34;&gt;When should I choose VPS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building a website or building a self built cloud storage and other &lt;strong&gt;web-based services&lt;/strong&gt; requires a computer that runs stably (around 7x24 hours on), a stable upstream bandwidth network connection, and a public IP address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measure the Speed Difference Between Http2 and Http3</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/measure-the-speed-difference-between-http2-and-http3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 12:48:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/measure-the-speed-difference-between-http2-and-http3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Http3 is the latest version of the HTTP protocol, which has undergone a significant improvement by using the QUIC (Fast UDP Network Connection) protocol at the transport layer to enhance performance, especially in high packet loss networks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Http3 will be officially standardized in 2022, and currently mainstream programming language standard libraries do not support http3.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the open-source libraries github.com/quic-go/quic-go/http3 available in the Go language, it is easy to build http3 clients and servers, making it easier to measure the speed difference between http2 and http3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go1.25 is worth paying attention to</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/go1.25-is-worth-paying-attention-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 20:57:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/go1.25-is-worth-paying-attention-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The development cycle of go1.25 has entered a release freeze, and generally there will be no new features. Currently, the author believes that the following are worth paying attention to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GOMAXPROCS now considers CPU limitations when running on containers, which is very useful when Go programs run on containers such as Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is now a new garbage collector as an experiment, which sets the environment variable GOEXPERIMENT=greenteagc to be enabled during construction, which improves performance in certain scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now for the value recovered after the panic, the value will not be printed repeatedly, which avoids the final output of the panic including duplicate content during testing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The experimental package testing/synctest has been completed and turned positive. Like other standard library packages, it guarantees backward compatibility according to the go1 compatibility commitment, providing support for testing concurrent code.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The compiler now uses DWARF version 5 to generate debugging information, which reduces the size of binary files generated during compilation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The net/http package has added an API to prevent cross site forgery attacks (CSRF).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set the environment variable GOEXPERIMENT=jsonv2 during construction to experience the v2 version of the JSON package being used.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does the metrics package record the number of non default behavior occurrences</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/howdoesthemetricspackagerecordthenumberofnondefaultbehavioroccurrences-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 14:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/howdoesthemetricspackagerecordthenumberofnondefaultbehavioroccurrences-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-the-metrics-package-record-the-number-of-non-default-behavior-occurrences&#34;&gt;How does the metrics package record the number of non default behavior occurrences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go1.21 is currently under development, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tip.golang.org/doc/go1.21&#34;&gt;draft release note&lt;/a&gt;It is mentioned that it is expected to be released in August 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the development branch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go&#34;&gt;go1.21&lt;/a&gt; In, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pkg.go.dev/runtime/metrics@master&#34;&gt;metrics&lt;/a&gt;  package, a series of indicators in the format /godebug/non-default-behavior/(godebug-name):events ,(godebug name) is a series of key value pairs for GODEBUG environment variables, and the names of certain keys, such as the execerrdot introduced in go1.19 (hereinafter referred to as &lt;strong&gt;godebug indicator&lt;/strong&gt;). &lt;strong&gt;Through these newly added indicators, the number of non default behavior occurrences caused by setting these environmental variables can be obtained.&lt;/strong&gt; This article analyzes how this is achieved by studying the source code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiplication_or_dereference</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/multiplication-or-dereference-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/multiplication-or-dereference-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitee.com/u-language/u-language&#34;&gt;U Language Project&lt;/a&gt; A separator based lexical analyzer is implemented in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitee.com/u-language/u-language/blob/master/pkg/lex/README.md&#34;&gt;Lexical Analyzer Design Document&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;The current * will be parsed as a multiplication sign, and when there is no pointer, there is no problem.&amp;rdquo;. Now we are ready to add pointers to this project. If you use * to dereference as in other languages, there are two options&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When constructing an abstract syntax tree, handle ambiguity where * can be both a multiplication sign and a dereference&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mmap_error</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/mmap-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 21:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/mmap-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-allows-handling-exception-page-errors&#34;&gt;Windows allows handling exception page errors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go1.21 is under development, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tip.golang.org/doc/go1.21&#34;&gt;draft release note&lt;/a&gt; Mention that it is expected to be released in August 2023&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the submitted information &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go/commit/e03ee85ef434f307500a71927dfb3e876161847a&#34;&gt;runtime: Allow handling of EXCEPTION_IN_PAGE_ERROR&lt;/a&gt; Go1.21 allows you to handle the access failure of the memory-mapped file through debug.SetPanicOnFault in Windows (for example, the drive where the memory-mapped file is located is ejected)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, it comes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go/issues/58457&#34;&gt;golang/go#58457&lt;/a&gt; Example of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Memory mapping files on external disks (using CreateFileMapping/MapViewOfFile)&#xA;Call debug. SetPanicOnFault (true)&#xA;Eject external disk&#xA;Attempt to read from memory map&#xA;What do you see?&#xA;The runtime faults (Exception 0xc0000006 0x0 &amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First blog</title>
      <link>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiulaidongfeng.github.io/en/one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software translation&#xA;On March 1, 2023, I published this blog&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
